Library of Congress Copyright Office Mask Work Deposits
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Library of Congress Copyright Office Mask Work Deposits 1985-1997
MSS85470
Library of Congress. Copyright Office
8,000 items
16 record center cartons
19.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
A representative sampling of mask works (schematic plans or layouts of an integrated circuit or computer chip) deposited with the Library of Congress Copyright Office.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
Organizations
Library of Congress. Copyright Office.
Subjects
Integrated circuit layout.; Integrated circuits--Design and construction.
Provenance
The Library of Congress Copyright Office Mask Work Deposits were transferred from the Library of Congress Copyright Office in 2009.
Access and Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division for information concerning these restrictions. In addition, many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The Library of Congress Copyright Office Mask Work deposits span the years 1985-1997. The collection consists of a representative sampling of mask works (schematic plans or layouts of an integrated circuit or computer chip) deposited with the Library of Congress Copyright Office. Per the Semiconductor Chip Protection Act of 1984, mask works are deposited with the Copyright Office by their manufacturers. The Copyright Office is obligated to retain the designs thirteen years after registration. Because Copyright Records Management was ready to dispose of the mask works it was no longer obligated to keep, the Manuscript Division decided to retain them by transfer. The Manuscript Division retained a representative sampling (every twentieth deposit) rather than accept the entire transfer.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged by registration number. The registration numbers reflect the range of numbers within each container, from the first item registered in the container to the last.
Container List
- 1-1260, 1985, May-1985,Oct. (Box RC 1)
- 1280-2060, 1985, Nov.-1986,Oct. (Box RC 2)
- 2076-2600, 1986, Oct.-1987, Mar. (Box RC 3)
- 2617-3480, 1987, Apr.-1988, Mar. (Box RC 4)
- 3500-4380, 1988, Mar.-1989, Feb. (Box RC 5)
- 4400-5420, 1989, Feb.-1989, Sept. (Box RC 6)
- 5440-6160, 1989, Dec.-1990, Aug. (Box RC 7)
- 6180-6760, 1990, Aug.-1991, Feb. (Box RC 8)
- 6780-7380, 1991, Oct.-1992, Apr. (Box RC 9)
- 7400-7860, 1991, Oct.-1992, Apr. (Box RC 10)
- 7880-8920, 1992, Apr.-1993, Apr. (Box RC 11)
- 8940-9640, 1993, Apr.-1994, Jan. (Box RC 12)
- 9660-10400, 1994, Feb.-1994, Oct. (Box RC 13)
- 10420-11500, 1994, Oct.-1995, Dec. (Box RC 14)
- 11520-12620, 1995, Dec.-1996, Sept. (Box RC 15)
- 12640-13080, 1996, Dec.-1997, June (Box RC 16)